Guide to the Alfred E. Heller Collection of World's Fair Material
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Alfred E. Heller collection of world's fair material
1851-2005
GEN MSS 734
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
45
(48 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
The collection consists of photographs, picture postcards, printed ephemera and other printed material collected by Alfred E. Heller documenting international fairs and exhibitions held around the world between 1851 and 2005. Photographs, picture postcards, and printed ephemera depict the locations and attractions of individual fairs and exhibitions, particularly those held in Europe and America during the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. Highlights include: photographs of the Paris Universal Exposition of 1878 taken by Hippolyte Auguste Collard and photographs of the Exposition universelle de 1889 (Paris, France) taken by the Neurdein Brothers. Files of printed material relating to late-twentieth century fairs and exhibitions document aspects of the planning, promotion and publicity associated with each. Extensive documentation can be found for the Louisiana World Exposition (1984: New Orleans, Louisiana), Expo 86 (1986: Vancouver, British Columbia), Expo '88 (1988: Brisbane, Queensland), Exposición Universal de 1992 (1992: Seville, Spain), Expo '98 (1998: Lisbon, Portugal), and Expo 2000 (2000: Hannover, Germany), among others.
Heller, Alfred E.
Collard, Hippolyte Auguste
Neurdein frères
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from William Reese Company on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2005-2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 47 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
For related material collected by Alfred E. Heller that is part of the Yale Collection of Western Americana, search the Uncataloged Acquisitions Database by entering "Ex libris Alfred Heller" in the Notes field and limiting the search to "archives and manuscripts" and "photographs."
Alfred Heller
Alfred Edward Heller (born 1929) is a collector, investor, and writer. He is the author of "World's Fairs and the End of Progress" (1999) and was the publisher and editor of the quarterly magazine World's Fair from 1981 to 1995.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of photographs, picture postcards, printed ephemera and other printed material collected by Alfred E. Heller documenting international fairs and exhibitions held around the world between 1851 and 2005. Photographs, picture postcards, and printed ephemera depict the locations and attractions of individual fairs and exhibitions, particularly those held in Europe and America during the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. Highlights include: photographs of the Paris Universal Exposition of 1878 taken by Hippolyte Auguste Collard and photographs of the Exposition universelle de 1889 (Paris, France) taken by the Neurdein Brothers. Files of printed material relating to late-twentieth-century fairs and exhibitions document aspects of the planning, promotion and publicity associated with each. Extensive documentation can be found for the Lousiana World Exposition (1984: New Orleans, Louisiana), Expo 86 (1986: Vancouver, British Columbia), Expo '88 (1988: Brisbane, Queensland), Exposición Universal de 1992 (1992: Seville, Spain), Expo '98 (1998: Lisbon, Portugal), and Expo 2000 (2000: Hannover, Germany), among others.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Photographs and Other Material, 1873-1933, 1981. II. Picture Postcards, 1851-2000. III. Printed Material, 1851-2005.
Exhibitions; Fairs; Photographic prints; Picture postcards; Printed ephemera; Born digital; Electronic documents; Collard, Hippolyte Auguste; Heller, Alfred E.; Neurdein frères; California Pacific International Exposition ( 1935-1936 San Diego, Calif.); Centennial Exhibition ( 1876 Philadelphia, Pa.); Century 21 Exposition ( 1962 Seattle, Wash.); Century of Progress International Exposition ( 1933-1934 Chicago, Ill.); Expo (International Exhibitions Bureau) ( 1967 Montréal, Québec); Expo (International Exhibitions Bureau) ( 1974 Spokane, Wash.); Expo (International Exhibitions Bureau) ( 1986 Vancouver, B.C.); Expo (International Exhibitions Bureau) ( 1988 Brisbane, Qld.); Expo (International Exhibitions Bureau) ( 1998 Lisbon, Portugal); Expo (International Exhibitions Bureau) ( 2000 Hannover, Germany); Exposition coloniale internationale de Paris ( 1931); Expo (International Exhibitions Bureau) ( 1992 Seville, Spain); Exposition universelle de 1889 ( Paris, France); Exposition universelle ( 1900 Paris, France); Golden Gate International Exposition ( 1939-1940 San Francisco, Calif.); International Specialized Exhibition "Christopher Columbus, Ships and the Sea" ( 1992 Genoa, Italy); Louisiana World Exposition ( 1984 New Orleans, La.); New York World's Fair ( 1939-1940 New York, N.Y.); New York World's Fair ( 1964-1965 New York, N.Y.); Exposition universelle de 1878 ( Paris, France); Panama-Pacific International Exposition ( 1915 San Francisco, Calif.); World's Columbian Exposition ( 1893 Chicago, Ill.); World's Fair of 1982 ( Knoxville, Tenn.); Vienna International Exhibition ( 1873)
- Photographs and Other Material, 1873-1933, 1981; Series I; (13 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I. is largely arranged in chronological order by date of exhibition.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. consists of contemporary black and white photographs and color prints documenting the locations and attractions of various international expositions held in Europe and America during the late nineteenth and early twentieth century. Some printed material is also present. Highlights include: photographs of the Paris Universal Exposition of 1878 taken by Hippolyte Auguste Collard and photographs of the Exposition universelle de 1889 (Paris, France) taken by the Neurdein Brothers.
  - Vienna International Exhibition (1873) (Box 1 Oversize)
    Color print of the interior of the Rotunda, "Die Rotunde des weltausstellungs-Gebaudes", sculpted by C. Rorich & Sohn & J.M. Kolb.
    Color print of fair grounds, "Das Weltausstellungsgebäude in Wein", sculpted by C. Rorich & Sohn.
    Black and white print of various exposition attractions, published and printed by Joseph Huppmann.
  - Centennial Exhibition (1876: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania)
    - Black and white photographs, 1876 (Box 2)
      Two photographs of the Centennial Exhibition from the George's Hill Observatory by James Cremer.
      One photograph of the Horticultural Grounds by Edward L. Wilson.
    - "Blueprints" newsletter centerfold depicting John McArthur, Jr. and Joseph M. Wilson proposal for the main exhibition hall for the 1876 Philadelphia Exposition., 1981 (Box 2)
  - Paris Universal Exposition of 1878, black and white photographs by Hippolyte Auguste Collard, mounted and titled (Box 3 Oversize)
    Partie du Parc du Champs de Mars: Chalet Tricotel
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Belgique
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Russie et Suisse
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Begique (alternate view)
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Autriche & Hongrie
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Grèce, Danemarck, Amérique Centrale & Méridionale
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Pavillon de Walter Scott et Canada
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: États-Unis D'Amérique, Suéde & Norvège
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Pavillon du Prince de Galles
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Portugal
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Espagne
    Vue des Façades de la rue des Nations: Siam, Tunis, Monaco, Portugal, Pays-Bas
    Vue du Champs de Mars
    Galerie Italienne: Du Palais du Champs-de-Mars
    Porte des Beaux-Arts
    Galerie d'Honneur: Du Palais du Champ-de-Mars
    Partie du Parc du Champ de Mars: Monaco & Espagne
    Pavillon des Eaux & Forêts
    Vue Générale du Champs de Mars
    Partie du Parc du Champ de Mars: Petit-Pont
  - Exposition universelle de 1889 (Paris, France), black and white photographs by the Neurdein Brothers, mounted with captions, 2 (Box 4 Oversize)
    Histoire de l'Habitation Humaine par Ch. Garnier: Maison Byzantine
    Café Marocain vors la Rue du Caire
    Terrasse des Beaux-Arts
    Palais de l'Exposition des Colonies
    Histoire de l'Habitation Humaine par Ch. Garnier: Maison Russe
    Histoire de l'Habitation Humaine par Ch. Garnier
    Histoire de l'Habitation Humaine par Ch. Garnier: Maison Mahométane
    Le Pavillion des Foréts
    Pavillon de l'Industrie du Gaz
    Pavillon de la Ville de Paris
    Porte d'Entrée de l'Esplanade des Invalides
    Pavillon du Vénézuéla
    Le Pavillon des Indes Anglaises
    Pavillons Chinois et Japonais
    Palais de l'Exposition Chinoise
    Souks Marocains
    Pavillons de l'Isthme de Suez
    Taillerie de Diamants Boas frères
    Chinoise Panthéon
    Pavillon des Indes Anglaises
    Palais des Colonies
    Palais de l'Hygiène
    Pavillon Norvégien
    Galerie des Industries Diverses, Porte d'Entrée de la Classe 20 (Céramique)
    Porte Principale du Pavillon de la République Argentine
    Le Dôme Central (Bouvard, Architecte)
    Porte Monumentale de la Classe 24 (Orfèvrerie)
    Palais de l'Exposition du Brésil
    Galerie de la Grande-Bretagne
    Galerie des Industries Diverses, Porte d'Entrée de la Classe 41 (Métallurgie)
    Pavillon du Nicaragua
    Pavillon du Salvador
    Pavillon du Chili
    Palais de 'Exposition du Ministère de la Guerre
    Le Vestibule du Palais des Beaux-Arts
  - Exposition universelle de 1889 (Paris, France), black and white photographs by the Neurdein Brothers, mounted with captions (Box 5 Oversize)
    Vue sur Auteuil, prise de la Tour Eiffel
    Bazars Algériéns
    Maison Rustique
    Histoire de l'Habitation Humaine, Maison Hindoue
    Le Palais des Beaux-Arts
  - Exposition universelle internationale de 1900 (Paris, France), 1893, 1900
    - Black and white photographs, 1900 (Box 6)
    - Printed ephemera, 1893, 1900 (Box 7 Oversize)
      Also includes an item, "The Dream City," relating to the 1893 World's Columbian Exposition (Chicago, Illinois).
    - Photograph album containing sixty-nine mounted photographs of delegates to the exposition by Eugene Pirou, 1900 (Box 8 Oversize)
    - Photograph album containing twenty-four photographs with captions, 1900 (Box 9)
  - Various Paris Expositions, 1867-1900
    - Black and white photographs and ephemera, 1867-1900 (Box 10 Oversize)
      "Exposition Universelle 1867 Paris," photograph by Pierre Pétit
      "Palais des Nations Étrangères, Colonie des Pays-Bas," photograph by Neurdien, Exposition Universelle 1900
      "La Salle des Fêtes," photograph, Exposition Universelle 1900
      "Le Panorama du Tour du Monde (Façade Principale)," color print, circa 1900
      "Supplement To The Illustrated London News, July 6 - Paris 1867," folding panoramic print, Exposition Universelle 1867
      "PUCK. - Welcome To The Fair!," World's Columbian Exposition of 1893 (Chicago, Illinois)
    - Heliogravure - Exposition Universelle 1878 (Box 11 Broadside)
  - Exposition coloniale internationale de Paris (1931), black and white photographs, 1932 (Box 12)
    Pavillon de la Tunisie, 1932
    Une fontaine lumineuse, 1932
  - Century of Progress International Exposition (1933-1934: Chicago, Illinois), black and white photographs, photostats, and clipping, 11 (Box 13 Oversize)
- Picture Postcards, 1851-2000s; Series II; (9 boxes)
  Series II. is not arranged in any particular order.
  Series II. includes original and reprinted picture postcards depicting places or scenes from various international and national exhibitions, expositions, and fairs.
  - California Pacific Exposition San Diego (San Diego, California), 1936 (Box 14)
  - United Kingdom - Austrian Exhibition (London, England), 1906 (Box 14)
  - The Corn Belt Exposition building (Mitchell, South Dakota), 1910 (Box 14)
  - California's Diamond Jubilee (San Francisco, California), 1925 (Box 14)
  - International Hygiene Exhibition (Dresden, Germany), 1911 (Box 14)
  - Exposition universelle internationale de 1900 (Paris, France) (Box 14)
  - Exposition internationale (1937: Paris, France) (Box 14)
  - Great Lakes Exposition (Cleveland, Ohio), 1936 (Box 14)
  - New York World's Fair (1939-1940), 8 (Box 14)
  - New York World's Fair (1964-1965) (Box 15)
  - Oregon Centennial Exposition and International Trade Fair (Portland, Oregon), 1959 (Box 15)
  - Czechoslovak General Exhibition (Prague, Czechoslovakia), 1991 (Box 15)
  - World's Columbian Exposition (1893: Chicago, Illinois) (Box 15)
  - Postcard File box, 1851-1985 (Box 16)
    Includes file dividers for which in some cases there are no contents.
    - Great Exhibition of the Works of Industry of All Nations (London, England), 1851
    - "New York, 1853" (empty)
    - "London, 1862" (empty)
    - "Paris, 1867" (empty)
    - "Vienna, 1873" (empty)
    - Centennial Exhibition (1876: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), 1985
    - "Paris, 1878" (empty)
    - "New Orleans, 1884" (empty)
    - "Melbourne, 1888" (empty)
    - "Paris, 1889" (empty)
    - "San Francisco, 1891" (empty)
    - World's Columbian Exposition (1893: Chicago, Illinois)
    - "San Francisco, 1894" (empty)
    - "Antwerp, 1894" (empty)
    - "Berlin, 1896" (empty)
    - "Geneva, 1896" (empty)
    - Exposition Internationale Bruxelles-Tervueren (1897)
    - "Leipzig, 1897" (empty)
    - "Omaha, 1898" (empty)
    - Exposition universelle internationale de 1900 (Paris, France)
    - Pan-American Exposition (1901: Buffalo, New York)
    - "Glasgow, 1901" (empty)
    - "Venice, 1901" (empty)
    - "Düsseldorf, 1902"
      This folder actually contains postcards from the Cork International Exhibition, circa 1902.
    - "Nantes, 1904" (emtpy)
    - "Breslau, 1902" (empty)
    - Düsseldorf Industrie Kunstausstellung (Düsseldorf, Germany), 1904
    - Louisiana Purchase Exposition (1904: St. Louis, Missouri)
    - Exposition universelle et internationale (1905: Liège, Belgium)
    - Lewis & Clark Centennial Exposition (1905: Portland, Oregon)
    - Exposition coloniale (Marseille, France), 1906
    - "Bucharest, 1906" (empty)
    - "Milan, 1906" (empty)
    - International Exhibition (1906-1907: Christchurch, New Zealand)
    - Jubiläums-Landes-Ausstellung-Nürnberg (Nuremberg, Germany), 1906
    - "Brunswick, 1907" (empty)
    - Exposition Internationale de Bordeaux (Bordeaux, France), 1907
    - Irish International Exhibition (1907: Dublin, Ireland)
    - Jamestown Ter-centennial Exposition (1907: Norfolk, Virginia)
    - "Mannheim, 1907" (empty)
    - "Graz, 1908" (empty)
    - Exposição Nacional de 1908 (Rio de Janeiro, Brazil)
    - Franco-British Exhibition (1908: London, England)
    - Ausstellung München (Munich, Germany), 1910
    - "Troy, 1908" (empty)
    - "Edinburgh, 1908" (empty)
    - "Toulouse, 1908" (empty)
    - Konstindustriutstallningen (Stockholm, Sweden), 1909
    - "Cleveland, 1909" (empty)
    - Hudson-Fulton Celebration (New York, New York), 1909
    - Imperial International Exhibition (London, England), 1909
    - Portolá Festival (San Francisco, California), 1909
    - Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition (1909: Seattle, Washington)
    - Exposition Suisse d'Agriculture (Lausanne, Switzerland), 1910
    - Exposition universelle et internationale (1910: Brusselles, Belgium)
    - "Chicago, 1910" (empty)
    - Japan-British Exhibition (1910: London, England)
    - "Pittsburgh, 1910" (empty)
    - "Cincinnati, 1910" (empty)
    - "San Francisco, 1910" (empty)
    - "Charlerdi, 1911" (empty)
    - "Columbus, 1911" (empty)
    - Scottish Exhibition, Art and Industry (Glasgow, Scotland), 1911
    - "London, 1911" (empty)
  - Various, 1901-1904 (Box 16)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Buffalo 1901, Düsseldorf 1902 and Düsseldorf 1904.
  - Various, 1908-1909; 4 (Box 16)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Edinburgh 1908, Hudson-Fulton 1909, London 1909 and Alaska-Yukon-Pacific 1909.
  - Various, 1903-1907; 5 (Box 16)
  - Various, 1851-1897; 3 (Box 16)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: London 1851, New York 1853, Paris 1878, San Francisco 1891, Chicago 1893, Geneva 1896 and Brussells 1897.
  - Various, 1910; 4 (Box 17)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Brussells 1910 and the Japan-British Exhibition 1910.
  - Various, 1907-1908; 4 (Box 17)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Jamestown 1907, Rio de Janeiro 1908 and London 1908.
  - Postcard File box, 1935-1962 (Box 18)
    - Century 21 Exposition (1962: Seattle, Washington)
    - Exposition universelle et internationale (1935: Brussels, Belgium)
    - California Pacific International Exposition (1935-1936: San Diego, California)
    - Texas Centennial (1936: Dallas, Texas)
    - Exposition Internationale (1937: Paris, France)
    - Great Lakes Exposition (Cleveland, Ohio), 1937
    - Empire Exhibition (1938: Glasgow, Scotland)
    - Schweizerische Landesausstellung (1939: Zürich, Switzerland)
    - New York World's Fair (1939-1940)
    - Exposition du Progrès Social (Lille, France), 1939
    - Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940: San Francisco, California)
    - Schweizerische Landesausstellung (Zürich, Switzerland), 1939
    - Canadian National Exhibition (Toronto, Canada), 1947
    - Chicago Railroad Fair (Chicago, Illinois), 1949
    - Festival of Britain (1951)
  - Louisiana World Exposition, 1935-1984 (Box 18)
  - Toronto and Yokohama, 1922 (Box 18)
  - World's Fair of 1982 (Knoxville, Tennessee), 2 (Box 18)
  - Various, 1882-1974 (Box 18)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Bordeaux 1882, Paris 1937, San Francisco 1939, Brussells 1958, and Spokane 1974.
  - Lake Tahoe, Nevada, 1938; 2 (Box 18)
  - Various, 1878-1988; 2 (Box 18)
    Include postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Paris 1878, San Francisco 1915, California Pacific 1935, Paris 1937, New York 1939, San Francisco 1939, Brussells 1958, Montreal 1967, Spokane 1974 and Melbourne 1988.
  - Various, 1900-1909; 1967 (Box 19)
    Includes postcards from various expositions, including but not limited to: Paris 1900, St. Louis 1904, Alaska Yukon Pacific 1909 and Montreal 1967.
  - Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940: San Francisco, California) and New York World's Fair (1939-1940) (Box 19)
  - Various, 1903-1993 (Box 19)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Paris 1903, Brussells 1910, Antwerp 1930, Paris 1937, New York 1939, Prague 1991 and Stuttgart 1993.
  - Expo '93 (Taejon, South Korea), 1993 (Box 19)
  - Postcard File box, 1958-1974 (Box 20)
    - Exposition universelle et internationale (1958: Brussels, Belgium)
    - Century 21 Exposition (1962: Seattle, Washington)
    - Expo 1964 (Lausanne, Switzerland)
    - New York World's Fair (1964-1965)
    - Alaska Centennial Exposition (Fairbanks, Alaska), 1967
    - Expo 67 (Montreal, Quebec), 1967
    - HemisFair (1968: San Antonio, Texas)
    - Expo '70 (Osaka, Japan), 1970
    - Expo '74 (Spokane, Washington), 1974
  - Postcard File box, 1982-1984 (Box 20)
    - World's Fair of 1982 (Knoxville, Tennessee)
    - Louisiana World Exposition (1984: New Orleans, Louisiana)
  - Postcard File box, 1985; 1988 (Box 21)
    Includes postcards associated with Expo '85 (Tsukuba, Japan) and Expo '88 (1988: Brisbane, Queensland).
  - Exposición Universal de 1992 (Seville, Spain), 5 (Box 21)
  - Various, circa 1905-1980s; 3 (Box 21)
    Includes postcards of the The Crystal Palace, built for the 1851 London Exhibition, as well as postcards from various other exhibitions, including but not limited to: Frankfurt 1899, Hungarian Exhibition Earls Court (1908), Oregon 1910, Japan-British Exhibition (1910), the California State Fair and the Texas State Fair (1936).
  - Various, circa 1900-1960s; 4 (Box 22)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Mardi Gras in New Orleans, the California State Fair, the Canadian National Exposition, the Pacific Southwest Exposition, Electric Park Kansas City, the International Trade Fair in Czechoslovakia, Tierpark Hagenbeck (1909), Valencia's Regional Expo (1909), Coney Island (circa 1913), Paris 1913, the National Orange Show (1932), the Los Angeles County Fair (1949), and the Mostra Internazionale d'Arte Cinematografica (Venice Film Festival, 1962).
  - Various, circa 1900-1968 (Box 22)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Paris 1900, Prague 1908, the Great Lakes Expo (Cleveland, 1937), Expo 1967 (Montreal, 1967), and HemisFair (San Antonio, 1968).
  - Exposición Ibero-Americana (1929-1930: Seville, Spain) and New York World's Fair (1939-1940), 1929; 1939 (Box 22)
  - Exposition Internationale (1937: Paris, France) (Box 22)
  - Various, 1894; 1902; 1934 (Box 22)
    Includes postcards from various exhibitions, including: the California Midwinter International Exposition of 1894, Canadian Wheat Arch (1902) and Century of Progress (Chicago, 1934).
  - "C of P Checklist, June 1993", 1964-1993 (Box 22)
    Includes both original and reprinted postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: the World's Columbian Exposition (1893: Chicago, Illinois), the California Midwinter International Exposition of 1894 (San Francisco), the New York World's Fair (1964-1965), the World's Fair of 1982 (Knoxville, Tennessee), Expo '86 (Vancouver, British Columbia), and the World Columbian Stamp Expo (1992).
  - Various, 1967-1980s (Box 22)
    Includes both original and reprinted postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Paris 1900, the Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940: San Francisco, California), the Texas World's Fair (1968) and Expo '70 (Osaka, Japan).
  - Various, 1939-2000 (Box 22)
    Includes both original and reprinted postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: the Louisiana Purchase Exposition (1904: St. Louis, Missouri), the Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940: San Francisco, California), Expo '58 (Brussels) and Expo 2000 (2000: Hannover, Germany).
  - Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940: San Francisco, California), 2 (Box 22)
  - Various, 1893; 1964; 1980s (Box 22)
    Includes both original and reprinted postcards from various exhibitions, including but not limited to: Paris International Fair (1878), the World's Columbian Exposition (1893: Chicago, Illinois) and the New York World's Fair (1964-1965).
  - World's Columbian Exposition (1893: Chicago, Illinois) and Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940: San Francisco, California), 1893; 1939 (Box 22)
  - Exposición Universal de 1992 (Seville, Spain) and Expo '93 (Taejon, South Korea), 1992-1993 (Box 22)
  - Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940: San Francisco, California) and Expo '93 (Taejon, South Korea), 1939-1940; 1993 (Box 22)
  - Various, circa 1900-1980s; 3 (Box 22)
- Printed Material, 1864-2005; Series III; (25 boxes)
  Series III. is arranged largely in chronological order according to fair. A group of miscellaneous material is arranged at the end of the series.
  Series III. consists of brochures, pamphlets, postcards, photographs, slides, advertisements and other printed material, largely documenting recognized World's Fairs which took place from 1853 to 2005. Included are both original and reprinted material. Material can also be found relating to earlier fairs and expositions, planned fairs that did not take place, and seemingly unofficial or unrecognized fairs.